<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LexicMap: efficient sequence alignment against millions of prokaryotic genomes​</title>
    <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/</link>
    <description>Recent content on LexicMap: efficient sequence alignment against millions of prokaryotic genomes​</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>kmers</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/utils/kmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/utils/kmers/</guid>
      <description>$ lexicmap utils kmers -h View k-mers captured by the masks Attentions: 1. Mask index (column mask) is 1-based. 2. K-mer positions (column pos) are 1-based. For reference genomes with multiple sequences, the sequences were concatenated to a single sequence with intervals of N&amp;#39;s. Usage: lexicmap utils kmers [flags] -d &amp;lt;index path&amp;gt; [-m &amp;lt;mask index&amp;gt;] [-o out.tsv.gz] Flags: -h, --help help for kmers -d, --index string ► Index directory created by &amp;#34;lexicmap index&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Searching</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/tutorials/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/tutorials/search/</guid>
      <description>Table of contents Table of contents TL;DR Input Hardware requirements Algorithm Parameters Steps Output Alignment result relationship Output format Examples TL;DR Build or download a LexicMap index.&#xA;Run:&#xA;For short queries like genes or long reads, returning top N hits.&#xA;lexicmap search -d db.lmi query.fasta -o query.fasta.lexicmap.tsv \ --min-qcov-per-genome 70 --min-match-pident 70 --min-qcov-per-hsp 70 --top-n-genomes 1000 For longer queries like plasmids, returning all hits.&#xA;lexicmap search -d db.lmi query.fasta -o query.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>search</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/search/</guid>
      <description>$ lexicmap search -h Search sequences against an index Attention: 1. Input should be (gzipped) FASTA or FASTQ records from files or stdin. Alignment result relationship: Query ├── Subject genome ├── Subject sequence ├── High-Scoring segment Pairs (HSP) ├── HSP segment Output format: Tab-delimited format with 18 columns. (The positions are 1-based). 1. query, Query sequence ID. 2. qlen, Query sequence length. 3. qstart, Start of alignment in query sequence. 4.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>subseq</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/utils/subseq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/utils/subseq/</guid>
      <description>Usage $ lexicmap utils subseq -h Exextract subsequence via reference name, sequence ID, position and strand Attention: 1. The option -s/--seq-id is optional. 1) If given, the positions are these in the original sequence. 2) If not given, the positions are these in the concatenated sequence. Usage: lexicmap utils subseq [flags] Flags: -h, --help help for subseq -d, --index string ► Index directory created by &amp;#34;lexicmap index&amp;#34;. -w, --line-width int ► Line width of sequence (0 for no wrap).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>seed-pos</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/utils/seed-pos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/utils/seed-pos/</guid>
      <description>Usage $ lexicmap utils seed-pos -h Extract seed positions via reference names Attentions: 0. This command requires the index to be created with the flag --save-seed-pos in lexicmap index. 1. Seed/K-mer positions (column pos) are 1-based. For reference genomes with multiple sequences, the sequences were concatenated to a single sequence with intervals of N&amp;#39;s. The positions can be used to extract subsequence with &amp;#39;lexicmap utils subseq&amp;#39;. 2. A distance between seeds (column distance) with a value of &amp;#34;-1&amp;#34; means it&amp;#39;s the first seed in that sequence, and the distance can&amp;#39;t be computed currently.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reindex-seeds</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/utils/reindex-seeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/utils/reindex-seeds/</guid>
      <description>Usage $ lexicmap utils reindex-seeds -h Recreate indexes of k-mer-value (seeds) data Usage: lexicmap utils reindex-seeds [flags] Flags: -h, --help help for reindex-seeds -d, --index string ► Index directory created by &amp;#34;lexicmap index&amp;#34;. --partitions int ► Number of partitions for re-indexing seeds (k-mer-value data) files. (default 512) Global Flags: -X, --infile-list string ► File of input file list (one file per line). If given, they are appended to files from CLI arguments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lexicmap</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/lexicmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/lexicmap/</guid>
      <description>$ lexicmap -h LexicMap: efficient sequence alignment against millions of prokaryotic genomes Version: v0.3.0 Documents: https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap Source code: https://github.com/shenwei356/LexicMap Usage: lexicmap [command] Available Commands: autocompletion Generate shell autocompletion scripts index Generate an index from FASTA/Q sequences search Search sequences against an index utils Some utilities version Print version information and check for update Flags: -h, --help help for lexicmap -X, --infile-list string ► File of input file list (one file per line).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>masks</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/utils/masks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/utils/masks/</guid>
      <description>$ lexicmap utils masks -h View masks of the index or generate new masks randomly Usage: lexicmap utils masks [flags] { -d &amp;lt;index path&amp;gt; | [-k &amp;lt;k&amp;gt;] [-n &amp;lt;masks&amp;gt;] [-s &amp;lt;seed&amp;gt;] } [-o out.tsv.gz] Flags: -h, --help help for masks -d, --index string ► Index directory created by &amp;#34;lexicmap index&amp;#34;. -k, --kmer int ► Maximum k-mer size. K needs to be &amp;lt;= 32. (default 31) -m, --masks int ► Number of masks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Motivation</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/notes/motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/notes/motivation/</guid>
      <description>BLASTN is not able to scale to millions of bacterial genomes, it&amp;rsquo;s slow and has a high memory occupation. For example, it requires &amp;gt;2000 GB for alignment a 2-kp gene sequence against all the 2.34 millions of prokaryotics genomes in Genbank and RefSeq.&#xA;Large-scale sequence searching tools only return which genomes a query matches (color), but they can&amp;rsquo;t return location information.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
