<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Usage on LexicMap: efficient sequence alignment against millions of prokaryotic genomes​</title>
    <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Usage on LexicMap: efficient sequence alignment against millions of prokaryotic genomes​</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>search</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/search/</guid>
      <description>$ lexicmap search -h Search sequences against an index Attention: 1. Input should be (gzipped) FASTA or FASTQ records from files or stdin. Alignment result relationship: Query ├── Subject genome ├── Subject sequence ├── High-Scoring segment Pair (HSP) Output format: Tab-delimited format with 17+ columns, with 1-based positions. 1. query, Query sequence ID. 2. qlen, Query sequence length. 3. hits, Number of subject genomes. 4. sgenome, Subject genome ID. 5. sseqid, Subject sequence ID.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>lexicmap</title>
      <link>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/lexicmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap/usage/lexicmap/</guid>
      <description>$ lexicmap -h LexicMap: efficient sequence alignment against millions of prokaryotic genomes Version: v0.4.0 Documents: https://bioinf.shenwei.me/LexicMap Source code: https://github.com/shenwei356/LexicMap Usage: lexicmap [command] Available Commands: autocompletion Generate shell autocompletion scripts index Generate an index from FASTA/Q sequences search Search sequences against an index utils Some utilities version Print version information and check for update Flags: -h, --help help for lexicmap -X, --infile-list string ► File of input file list (one file per line).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
